

# **Ayush Kaushik**

Date of birth: 29/07/1997 | Nationality: Indian | Gender: Male | Phone number:

(+91) 8210652078 (Mobile) | **Email address:** ayushcoshik@gmail.com | **LinkedIn:** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayush-kaushik-62008315a/

WhatsApp Messenger: +918210652078

Address: 303 Ragini residency Road No. 5D NSK Puri Patna, 800001, Patna,

India (Home)

# ABOUT ME

A cooperative team player and a proven leader with an experience in developing code effective, maintainable and scalable web applications. A technology geek with great enthusiasm to delve into new technologies and take up the challenge. Lately a cloud discoverer to probe and provide great results and service to add values.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

17/06/2021 - 11/09/2022 Kolkata, India

#### **SYSTEM ENGINEER TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES**

- Documented and managed critical server operations, ensuring the stability and availability of infrastructure components vital to business continuity. Handled and resolved urgent alerts promptly, employing tools like AutoSys, Orion, and ServiceNow to diagnose, troubleshoot, and mitigate issues efficiently.
- Interacted directly with US based clients to understand their infrastructure needs and requirements, providing one-on-one support, gathering specifications, and ensuring alignment with service level agreements (SLAs).
- Utilized ServiceNow for tracking and managing incidents, maintaining comprehensive records, and streamlining the incident resolution process.

12/09/2022 - CURRENT Kolkata, India

#### **CMS DEVELOPER TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES**

- Collaborated with a US-based client to understand their content management requirements and translate them into functional specifications for the website.
- Developed and maintained a robust Content Management System using ReactJS, ensuring a seamless and user-friendly interface for content editors to manage website content efficiently.
- Customized and implemented various features within the CMS, such as content publishing workflows,

media management, and user permissions, aligning them with the client's specific needs and industry standards.

• Conducted regular updates and maintenance tasks on the website, implementing enhancements and bug fixes to improve performance and reliability.

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

05/04/2013 - 20/05/2014 Patna, India

**SECONDARY SCHOOL EXAMINATION (YEAR : 2014)** GYAN NIKETAN VITTHAL VR CMPLX DANAPUR PATNA BR (08109)

Website https://www.gyanniketan.in/ | Field of study Education not further defined | Final grade 87.4%

10/04/2015 - 21/05/2016 Patna, India

SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (YEAR: 2016) GYAN NIKETAN VITTHAL VR CMPLX DANAPUR PATNA BR (08109)

Website https://www.gyanniketan.in/ | Field of study Education science | Final grade 74%

22/05/2016 - 28/05/2017 Patna, India

**SENIOR SCHOOL CERTIFICATE EXAMINATION (YEAR : 2017)** Private Candidate ( Appeared for Improvement)

Field of study Education science | Final grade 75.4%

02/10/2019 - 08/08/2020 Online, India

JAVA MASTER CRUX Coding blocks

Website <a href="https://codingblocks.com/">https://codingblocks.com/</a>

08/01/2021 - 13/07/2021 Online, India

**NAGARRO WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP** Coding Blocks

Website https://codingblocks.com/

03/02/2021 - 07/05/2021 Online . India

**FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER 2021** Udemy

Website https://www.udemy.com/

01/06/2017 - 02/08/2021 Amritsar, India

**BACHELORS OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING** Guru Nanak Dev University, Amritsar

Website https://online.gndu.ac.in/ | Field of study Computer Science and Engineering | Final grade 8.27

06/08/2022 - 08/01/2023 Online, India

**JAVASCRIPT THE ADVANCED CONCEPTS** Udemy

Website https://www.udemy.com/

# DIGITAL SKILLS

**Libraries and Programming languages** 

React.js and Javascript | HTML& CSS5+ | Javascript(Nodejs, ExpressJs) | Object-Oriented Programming | JavaScript

**Analytical** 

Data Structures | DATA STRUCTURES AND ALGORITHMS WITH JAVA

**SQL** and Tools

Mongodb / Mongoose | SQL(MySQL PostgreSQL) | Vs code | Eclipse 10, 11, 15.5 | GCP - Google Cloud Platform